Victor Misiko

5+ years of experience as a Software Developer, expertise in application design, development, deployment, implementation, testing, and maintenance of Enterprise web applications and mobile applications. Extensive SDLC experience including requirement analysis, design, coding, application implementation, unit testing, system testing, documentation, and production support. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create reliable and user- friendly systems.

Contact Information

Email: victormisiko.vm@gmail.com

Phone: 254721649416 Location: Nairobi, Kenya

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/victor-misiko-32101212b

Skills

Languages: Typescript(Proficient), Javascript(Proficient), Python(Proficient), Go(intermediate), Dart(intermediate), Java(intermediate)

Frameworks/Tools: Vuejs, Nuxtjs, Reactjs, Nextjs, Flutter, Adonisjs, Django, FastApi, Quarkus, Go-toolkit, Fiber

Version Control: Git

Cloud: AWS, Azure

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, H2, MongoDB

Observability: ELK Stack, Datadog, Sentry and Firebase Crashlytics.

IDEs: VS Code, IntelliJ, Android Studio, XCode.

Operating Systems: Linux(Proficient), Windows(Proficient), macOS(Proficient)

Work experience

Aug 2020 - Present

Sendy (Software Engineer (Full-time))

Tools/Skills- Vue.js React Flutter Go Java

Sendy is a logistics - last mile delivery and fulfillment pan-African company that makes it easier for businesses to trade by handling all their logistics and fulfillment pain points.

Responsibility:

- Responsible for all things payments and finance, ensuring PCI DSS compliance and direct integration with payment service providers to process payment requests
- Built the Sendy Payment UI library used across different organization applications (Flutter and Vuejs Payment UI plugins)
- Improved payment efficiency and reliability across the platform, increasing success rate from 50% to 90%
- Developed language support for library applications used by different countries across the continent
- Reviewed peer code, debugging and refactored, Identifying, prioritizing, executing and assigning tasks
- Automating tasks through CI/CD pipelines
- Initiated language support to help in expansions to the rest of the other African countries.

• Writing Unit tests, Integration tests and end to end tests to ensure shipment of well tested code.

May 2019 - Present

Ascend Tech House (Co-Founder - Software Engineer)

Tools/Skills- Next.js Django GraphQL DOCKER AWS CI/CD

Ascend tech house is a Kenya-based company building all interesting software for modern companies, one of our products being legal. E-legal is a law firm management system that helps to easier digitisation, automation of processes in law firms and reduction of volumes of paper work by handling Court Matters Files, General case Files, Staff Management, Billing, Invoices, Management of Clients to make the law firm processes easier and flawless.

Responsibility:

- Involved in software ideation of an E-legal platform
- Building an E-legal law firm management system that digitizes, automates processes and reduces paperwork for law firms.

May 2019 - Present

Essay-Genius (C.E.O - Full Stack Engineer (part-time))

Tools/Skills- Vue.js AdonisJs Docker AWS CI/CD

Essay-genius is a freelancing platform that connects clients with freelancers. This platform enables a user's who have tasks that they want to be helped with, The freelancers include, tutors, Web developers, and Data analysts among others.

Responsibility:

- Design UX and create user flow to enhance user journey for both user personas in the platform
- System Design Architecture for the backend in order to fulfill the requirement of the frontend and UX design
- Integration with Postgresql database
- Continuous Integration and Continuous Development with GitLab pipelines for both frontend and backend technology Integration with AWS services, such as SES, S3 buckets and EC2 Instances
- Using Docker for building Images for easier deployment for Ec2 Instances

Oct 2020 - Feb 2022

QuantumGrad (Backend Engineer (part-time))

Tools/Skills - Python, FastAPI, REST, React, Docker AWS

QuantumGrad is a quantum computing platform that houses all things related to quantum computing in one platform. This includes Articles, Publications, News, Events, and jobs among others.

This platform is for Quantum computing enthusiasts, researchers, students, and Quantum computing content writers who wish to share their knowledge by writing articles in Quantum Grad

Responsibility:

- Work with UX and Frontend Engineers to come up with good backend System architecture that covers and Fulfills all the UX and frontend requirements from the backend.
- Identify which database is best suitable for use.
- Write clean code using MVC Architecture to provide guidance and clarity in the code architecture

for easier maintainability.

- Integrating with AWS services such as S3 Buckets, and SES among EC2 Instances.
- Using Docker to build docker images for CI/CD deployment to the AWS EC2 Instances.
- Monitoring and Maintenance of the servers.

Education

Machakos University Aug 2015 - Oct 2019 Bachelor of Science (BSc), Statistics and Programming

Friends School Kamusinga Jan 2011 - Oct 2014 High School Diploma